Guide to the Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk Photographs of Theatrical Performers Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk photographs of theatrical performers collection
1927-1930
YCAL MSS 267
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.21
Promotional photographs of theater performers collected by sisters Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk, 1927-1930. The Schlenk sisters were cast members of the musical, Gay Paree, directed by Jacob J. Shubert. Many of the photographs are portraits of their fellow cast members, as well as other theatrical performers. Portraits of individuals include the Schlenk sisters, as well as James Allatin, Alice Boulden, Irene Cornell, Patsy Costello, Dulcy Dowd, Bobby Pinkus, James Rennie, Charles "Chic" Sale, Richard Bernard "Red" Skelton, Eric Titus, Lillian Ward, and Lorraine Weimar. Interior group portraits show the cast of Gay Paree at Bob Berger's, a restaurant in Boston, Massachusetts, 1928. The collection includes a program for Gay Paree at the Shubert Theatre February 6, 1928.
Schlenk, Josephine, b. 1908
Schlenk, Sophie, b. 1910
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ian Brabner, Bookseller, on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Promotional photographs of theater performers collected by sisters Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk, 1927-1930. The Schlenk sisters were cast members of the musical, Gay Paree, directed by Jacob J. Shubert. Many of the photographs are portraits of their fellow cast members.
Arrangement
Photographs arranged alphabetically by the surname of the performer, followed by individuals with unidentified surnames, group portraits. The collection includes a program for Gay Paree at the Shubert Theatre February 6, 1928.
Actors -- Portraits; Dancers -- Pictorial works; Dancers -- Portraits; Entertainers -- Pictorial works; Entertainers -- Portraits; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Theatrical companies -- Pictorial works; Photographic prints; Studio portraits; Allatin, James, b. 1905 -- Portraits; Boulden, Alice -- Portraits; Cornell, Irene -- Portraits; Costello, Patsy -- Portraits; Dowd, Dulcy -- Portraits; Pinkus, Bobby, b. 1908 -- Portraits; Rennie, James, 1890-1965 -- Portraits; Sale, Charles, 1885-1936 -- Portraits; Schlenk, Josephine, b. 1908 -- Portraits; Schlenk, Sophie, b. 1910 -- Portraits; Shubert, Jacob J., 1878?-1963 -- Portraits; Skelton, Red, 1913-1997 -- Portraits; Titus, Eric -- Portraits; Ward, Lillian -- Portraits; Weimar, Lorraine -- Portraits
- Photographs, 1927-1930; Series I; 35
  Arrangement
  Photographs arranged alphabetically by the surname of the performer, followed by individuals with unidentified surnames, and group portraits.
  Scope and Contents
  Promotional photographs of theater performers collected by sisters Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk
  - Allatin, James (b. 1905), circa 1927; 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Inscriptions to Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk
    Photograph by Strand, New York City, New York
    Biographical/Historical note
    Member of Give and Take Show, 1926-1927
  - Boulden, Alice, 1930; 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Inscription to Josephine Schlenk and Sophie Schlenk
    Photograph by Rayhuff Richter, Chicago, Illinois
  - Cornell, Irene, 1928; 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Photograph by H. Golden, 104 Hanover Street, Boston, Massachusetts
    Images depicts her body covered in gold paint for a dance performance entitled "The Gold Plaque"
  - Costello, Patsy, 1927; 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Inscription to Josephine Schlenk
    Photograph by Hixton Studios, Kansas City, Missouri
  - Dowd, Dulcy, 1927; 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Photographs by James Hargis Connelly, Chicago, Illinois
  - Pinkus, Bobby (b. 1908), circa 1927; 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Photographs by Strand, New York City, New York
    Born Peter James Accardy, later known as Peter James
  - Rennie, James (1890-1965), 1930, Mar; 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Inscription to Miss Schlenk
  - Sale, Charles "Chic" (1885-1936), no date; 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Schlenk, Josephine, and Sophie Schlenk, no date; 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Skelton, Red (1913-1997), no date; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Titus, Eric, 1928; 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Photographs by Paul Stine Raymor, Chicago, Illinois
  - Ward, Lillian, 1927; 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Weimar, Lorraine, circa 1927; 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Photographs by deBarron Studios, New York City, New York
  - Unidentified Surnames, circa 1927
    - Cookie, 1927, Aug 23; 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Margaret, circa 1927; 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Photograph by Herbert Mitchell, New York
    - Midge, circa 1927; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Photograph by Daguerre Studios, Chicago, Illinois
    - Tern, circa 1927; 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Photograph by Paul Stine Raymor, Chicago, Illinois
  - Group Photographs, circa 1927-1930
    - Interior group portraits of the cast of Gay Paree, 1928, Feb 28; 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Taken in Bob Berger's, a restaurant located at 256 Tremont Street, Boston, Massachusetts, adjacent to the Metropolitan Theatre
    - Exterior portrait of four women, two men, and a dog, circa 1927-1930; 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Taken in Jackson, Michigan
- Printed Material, 1928; Series II
  - Broad Street Theatre and Shubert Theatre Combined Programme Gay Paree, 1928, Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 20)